Matthew Sharpe

Full-Stack Web Developer | Graphic Designer

202-445-7615 mattsharpe72@gmail.com Washington, DC 20002

An experienced, dedicated and determined designer and web developer with an eye for detail. My journalism background instilled in me a respect for deadlines and a passion for getting things right. My inspiration comes from finding solutions to problems in a way that puts creativity front and center.

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly Student, Web Development Immersive, 2018

- · Full-stack web development program focused on best practices in object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling and test-driven development
- · Built a front-end Hangman game using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- · Built a full-stack web app designed to organize wine collections using Mongoose, Express, Handlebars and Node.js

USO, Arlington, VA

Design Specialist, 2013-2016

- · Art directed/designed On Patrol, a 72-page quarterly magazine
- · Designed print publications including newsletters, booklets, flyers, one-pagers, posters, postcards, photo books, greeting cards and banner-ups for internal and external clients
- · Designed web graphics, logos and social media materials

Stars and Stripes, Washington, DC

Copy Editor, 2007–2013

- Designed pages, edited copy and wrote headlines under daily deadlines for as many as four editions
- · Focused on design of Page 1, enterprise packages and display pages, along with covers for separate weekly publication
- · Collaborated with Art Department and story editors to create visually appealing treatments for daily and advance projects

Post and Courier, Charleston, SC Design Desk Chief, 2004–2007

- · Supervised staff of six Features designers, providing daily critiques and quality control, delegating assignments and organizing workflow, conducting annual reviews and setting short- and long-range goals
- · Designed fronts and inside pages for rotating Features sections

Sports Designer, 2003–2004

- · Designed front and inside pages for Sports section under deadline
- · Wrote headlines, edited articles, and selected wire stories and photos
- · Produced numerous special section covers and inside pages

The Augusta Chronicle, Augusta, GA Design Editor, 2000–2003

- · Led staff of 10 page designers, critiquing and approving work for publication on daily basis for Metro, Business and Sports sections
- · Served as lead designer, responsible for the front page four days a week
- · Oversaw redesign of newspaper during conversion to 50-inch web

SKILLS

Front-End Development HTML5 | CSS3 | CLI |avaScript | React | A|AX

Back-End Development Express | Mongoose Python | Node.js

DatabasesSQL | PostgreSQL

Graphics and Layout InDesign | Photoshop Illustrator | Acrobat

EDUCATION

General Assembly
Web Development Immersive

University of Georgia B.A., English

AWARDS

MarcomAwards, Platinum, Cover Design, 2014

EXCEL Awards, Bronze, Feature Design, 2014

South Carolina Press Association 3rd, Features Design, 2006 2nd, Sports Design, 2004 1st, Sports Design, 2003

Society of Newspaper Design Award of Excellence, 1999